Guide to the Peter R. Frank Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Peter R. Frank papers
1968-1990
SC0393
Frank, Peter R., 1924-
1 Linear feet
Material concerning exhibits, library acquisitions, the Visiting Professorships in German, Austrian, and Swiss Studies, administrative matters, and the Peace Studies group at Stanford.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Peter Frank, 1990.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Curator of Germanic collections at Stanford University Libraries, 1967-1990. Active with the faculty committee on Peace Studies, 1981-1990. Between 1974-1977 Frank was Editor-in-chief of the S. Fischer publishing house in West Germany.
Description of the Collection
Material concerning exhibits, library acquisitions, the Visiting Professorships in German, Austrian, and Swiss Studies, administrative matters, and the Peace Studies group at Stanford.
Access Terms
Baron, Salo Wittmayer, 1895-1989; Bernstein, Barton J.; Bernstein, Barton J.; Bland, Byron.; Bland, Byron.; Cremerius, Johannes.; Cremerius, Johannes.; Eitner, Lorenz.; Eitner, Lorenz.; Fellner, Fritz.; Fellner, Fritz.; Frank, Peter R., 1924-; Freud, Sigmund, 1856-1939.; Galtung, Johan.; Galtung, Johan.; Goethe-Institut (San Francisco, Calif.); Gordon, H. L. Jr.; Gordon, H. L. Jr.; Gordon, Nancy M.; Gordon, Nancy M.; Herring, Ron.; Herring, Ron.; Kennedy, Donald, 1931-; Kraus, Karl.; Kraus, Karl.; Kraus, Wolfgang.; Kraus, Wolfgang.; Lewis, John.; Lewis, John.; Lohnes, Walter F.W.; Mommsen, Katherina, 1925-; Paret, Peter.; Paret, Peter.; Portheim, Max von.; Portheim, Max von.; Schnitzler, Arthur, 1862-1931.; Schnitzler, Arthur,, 1862-1931.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Stanford University. Libraries--Exhibitions..; Stanford University. Libraries. Acquisitions.; Stanford University. Libraries. Collection Development Program; Stanford University. Libraries.; Ward, Robert.; Ward, Robert.
Collection Contents
- Papers, 1968-1990
  - Vienna Exhibit, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Freud Exhibit: Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Freud Exhibit: Materials, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 18th Century Exhibit, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Karl Kraus Exhibit, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Vienna Exhibit: Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Vienna Exhibit: Materials, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Exhibits, 1971-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Portheim Collection, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Schofield Collection, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - H.J. Gordon Gift (Militaria, German history), 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Baron Collection, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Germanic Collections at Stanford, 1974-1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Stanford Collection of German, Austrian, and Swiss Culture, 1977-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - German and Austrian Visiting Professorships: General, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Austrian Studies Visiting Professorship, 1972-1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Swiss Studies Visiting Professorship, 1978-1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - OLMS Microfilm Project, 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Resources Development, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Special Purchase Justifications, 1981-1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Peace Studies, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Peace Studies, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Peace Studies, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Peace Studies, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Peace Studies, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Peace Studies, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Peace Studies, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Peace Studies, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Peace Studies, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Peace Studies, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Peace Studies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Photo, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)